<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips on rData.lu - Specialized in data science training and expertise</title>
    <link>/categories/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tips on rData.lu - Specialized in data science training and expertise</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) rData.lu. All rights reserved. &lt;br&gt; Content reblogged by &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.r-bloggers.com/&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;R-bloggers&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional peace of mind</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-14-functional-peace-of-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-14-functional-peace-of-mind/</guid>
      <description>I think what I enjoy the most about functional programming is the peace of mind that comes with it. With functional programming, there’s a lot of stuff you don’t need to think about. You can write functions that are general enough so that they solve a variety of problems. For example, imagine for a second that R does not have the sum() function anymore. If you want to compute the sum of, say, the first 100 integers, you could write a loop that would do that for you:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How tidyeval could make your life easier</title>
      <link>/post/2017-08-27-how-tidyeval-could-make-your-life-easier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-08-27-how-tidyeval-could-make-your-life-easier/</guid>
      <description>First thing’s first: maybe you shouldn’t care about tidyeval. Maybe you don’t need it. If you exclusively work interactively, I don’t think that learning about tidyeval is important. I can only speak for me, and explain to you why I personally find tidyeval useful.
I wanted to write this blog post after reading this twitter thread and specifically this question.
Mara Averick then wrote this blogpost linking to 6 other blog posts that give some tidyeval examples.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>